Joshua Thomas Brooks

- 3431 Bethoven St. Pittsburgh, PA 15219
- 412-849-0522
- itbrooks210@gmail.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshuathomasbrooks/

Professional Summary

 A Supply Chain professional interested in supply chain, logistics, data science, transportation, economics, and financial//securities analysis with the education, experience, knowledge, and passion to improve supply chains through data, analytics, visibility, simplicity, continuous improvement, waste reduction, and communication.

Experience

- Intel Corporation (Nasdaq: INTC) 2/1/2022-6/1/2023
 - Primary point of contact for global suppliers; primarily located in Asia.
 - Responsible supplier spend: \$100M annually and >\$1B contract length
 - Eliminated backlog for critical supplier and removed them from daily task force meetings
 - 88% reduction in backlog in 3 months
 - Collaborate with tier 1 and tier 2 suppliers for NPI developments
- Koppers Inc. (NYSE: KOP) 10/1/2013-2/1/2022
 - Logistics Analyst II, Carbon Materials and Chemicals North America 1/1/2015-2/1/2022
 - Logistics Analyst I, Carbon Materials and Chemicals North America 10/1/2013-11/1/2015
 - Project Manager: TMS implementation (CH Robinson) and Supply Chain Network Optimization
 - Increased overall plant network utilization rates from 65% to close to 90% with annual fixed costs savings of \$30 million annually
 - Manager of company wide railcars 1,500 rail/tank cars with a total spend management of \$15M annually
 - Total lifetime hard savings of over \$4 million with more soft savings
 - Control Transportation 3PL, railcar lessor, and vendor freight and contractor spend management of \$25M annually
 - Identified, found, and recouped over \$3 million in transportation refunds
- University of Pittsburgh 1/1/2016-12/1/2017
 - Lean Six Sigma Blackbelt Mentor Consultant
 - Project sponsor for MBA Engineering student teams during the school sememster Lean Six Sigma Black Belt Certification class
 - Liason between project customer teams (TruFood Manufacturing for KIND Foods) and University of Pittsburgh MBA Six Sigma project team
 - Mentored team through DMAIC (Define, Measure, Analyze, Improve, and Control) Six Sigma process
 - Reduced packaging defects and cost of poor quality (COPQ); increasing customer (KIND) satisfaction and reducing overall throughput costs by 10%
 - Identified and corrected shift production variances by DPMO data 3rd shift was producing more DPMO's than 1st and 2nd shift
- Knichel Logistics 1/1/2013-12/1/2023
 - Intermodal Operations and Pricing Specialist Intern and full time employee
- <u>Hub Group</u> (NYSE: <u>HUBG</u>) 1/1/2012-12/1/2012
 - Highway Solutions Specialist Intern
- United States Postal Service (USPS) 1/1/2009-12/1/2011
- Mail Clerk / Mail Handler

Education and Certifications

- <u>Duquesne University</u>
 - Masters of Business Administration (MBA) 1/1/2013-12/1/2016
 - Bachelor of Science in Business Administration (BSBA) 1/1/2009-12/1/2013
 - Supply Chain Management major and Marketing minor
 - Self published my MBA thesis, <u>The Financial Risks of Supply Chain Disruptions</u> through Amazon Kindle Direct Publishing (KDP)
 - Supply Chain Risk Management (SCRM) focus
- University of Pittsburgh
 - Lean Six Sigma Certifications (LSSGB and LSSBB)
- EdX Data Science Professional Certificates
- DataCamp

- 34/439 datacamp data science classes completed as of 2/23/2024
- Duolingo
 - Actively learning several languages to advance my knowledge

Awards

- APICS/ASCM (Association for Supply Chain Management) Scholar Recipient, 12/1/2016
 - Competed against 40 national student scholars in a poster competition outlying supply chain project experience during the ASCSM national convention in Washington D.C.
- Oracle OTM (Oracle Transportation Management) Users Conference Scholar Recipient, Philadelphia, PA,12/ 2016
 - Selected as a scholar recipient along with 5 other national scholars who demonstrated prior work experience and excellence with Oracle OTM and awarded at Oracle's national convention in Philadelphia, PA
- 1st Place, General Electric Manufacturing Layout Competition, Design of Manufacturing Area Floorplan Incorporating Lean Manufacturing Processes
- Employee of the Month, Knichel Logistics, 10/1/2013

Volunteer and Membership

- Traffic Club of Pittsburgh President 1/1/2019-12/1/2019 First Vice President 1/1/2018-12/1/2018
 Second Vice President 1/1/2017-12/1/2017 Board Member 1/1/2016-12/1/2016
- Cherry City Volunteer Fire Company Fundraising Volunteer Service 1/1/2017-8/1/2023
- Juvenille Diabetes Research Foundation International (JDRF) Volunteer
- American Diabetes Association (ADA) Volunteer